<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" version="2.0">
    <channel>
        <title>File Systems - Tag - George&#39;s Blog</title>
        <link>georgesims21.github.io/tags/file-systems/</link>
        <description>File Systems - Tag - George&#39;s Blog</description>
        <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>zh-cn</language><copyright>©2019 Notepadium.</copyright><atom:link href="georgesims21.github.io/tags/file-systems/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" /><item>
    <title>FUSE</title>
    <link>georgesims21.github.io/posts/fuse/</link>
    <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 &#43;0000</pubDate>
    <author>Author</author>
    <guid>georgesims21.github.io/posts/fuse/</guid>
    <description><![CDATA[FUSE (filesystem in user space) [1] What is FUSE, and why use it? FUSE is an open source framework which allows you to build filesystems in user space, compared to the conventional kernel space route. Building in user space is said by many to not be suitable for production, and also that the overhead is too substantial to be of use. But this allows the programmer to work in a &lsquo;friendlier&rsquo; environment, gives a much larger toolset to work with and probably most importantly, it doesn&rsquo;t crash the system on a bug like kernel programming does.]]></description>
</item>
<item>
    <title>procfs/sysfs</title>
    <link>georgesims21.github.io/posts/procfs/</link>
    <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 &#43;0000</pubDate>
    <author>Author</author>
    <guid>georgesims21.github.io/posts/procfs/</guid>
    <description><![CDATA[procfs and sysfs are both pseudo filesystems located in the root directory of the Unix FS heirarchy. They contain files which act as a window to the kernel and allows user-land processes to see and change important system information. Upon inspection (if you wrote the command $ ls -al /proc on a Unix system) you would notice that all files are 0 in size. This is due to the window aspect, one a user-land process reads/opens one of these files, it is at that moment the kernel writes that information to the file, hence the analogy.]]></description>
</item>
</channel>
</rss>
